Hey, I am Nik Silver.
I am the founder of Silver AI Consulting,
and today I wanna talk about the
only AI implementation I think small
to medium-sized businesses should
be focusing on right now, which is
something called an AI operating system.
I wanna show you what it is, why it's such
a game changer for businesses, and how you
could get started on the journey towards
building your own AI operating system
by now most businesses have tried some
form of AI solution in their business.
This could be patching up an inefficiency
in your workflow or trying to solve
some form of bottleneck in your business
that is taking up a lot of your effort
and time and sure this might work
to some extent, but it's not really
providing the most amount of value
that I see AI provide for a business.
For AI to really be effective,
it needs to have proper context
and if you're only fixing one part of
your business, the AI will have context
on that specific part of your business.
But with an AI operating system, your
AI agents will not only have context on
one small part of your business, it will
have the context of your entire business.
You can think of it as an
operating system on your computer,
which hosts all your apps.
So in a similar fashion, the AI
operating system holds all your business
processes, all the tools you use, and
combines them into one coherent system
And the benefits of having an AI operating
system like this is that AI truly
understands your business as a whole.
It can look at your revenue numbers,
it can look at your marketing, your
sales call transcripts, and look
for opportunities where you are
leaving money on the table or where
you're missing out on opportunities
And at a high level, the way
the system works is that the AI
itself acts kinda like a brain.
It's the orchestrator of the system.
It will look at all the data
and come up with suggestions on
what it thinks should happen.
Then either it goes and do it
automatically, depending on the task,
or it, it presents the information to
you where you can make the decision.
Then it has access to tools
where it can actually go out
and take actions on your behalf.
And finally, and this is the most powerful
feature in my opinion, is the memory.
This means that the system
only gets smarter over time.
Unlike traditional software, this
actually improves over time and
becomes better the more you use it
for this example, we're going
to use an upcoming sales call.
So there's a trigger that happens
first, and that is when the prospect
gets booked onto your calendar.
This tells another AI agent that, hey,
we need to inform the user of the system
that they have an upcoming sales call.
But not only that, you're gonna have
another agent that's gonna go out
and do research on this prospect
by looking at their LinkedIn, their
official website, and then gonna fetch
back information that is relevant
for the context of the sales call.
And not only that, another agent
is going to have access to all
previous sales calls, so it knows
what type of objections comes up.
So this way, we can preemptively
address them before the even
prospect brings them up.
Coming into a sales call like
this is gonna prepare you a lot
better and is going to increase the
likelihood of you closing the sale.
Obviously, it's not a guarantee.
It depends on the skill of the
salesperson, obviously But for the sake
of this example, let's say that the
prospect is interested in working with us.
So once the call ends, that triggers
a new AI agent to draft a proposal
immediately for your review.
You'll go over it and make sure
that everything is in order, and
with the click of a button, you
will send that off to the prospect
In addition to this, the agent has
also provided a place for where the
prospect can put a signature and
a link to collect their payment.
And just like that, in one email,
they have the proposal, uh, the
ability to agree to the proposal
and pay all in one go, so you don't
have to have this back and forth.
And once they've accepted the proposal
and signed it and made a payment,
that is going to trigger the next
event, which is the onboarding flow.
And of course, once this process
is finished, it's going to log
each step in its memory so it,
it becomes better over time
So hopefully by sharing this example, it
has sparked your imagination and given
you an idea of what an AI operating
system can do for your business.
so here we are inside my own AI operating
system, and if you used AI before, this
is going to look very familiar to you.
It's essentially just a chat window,
but don't let that fool you because
there's a lot going on under the hood.
Here I can ask it questions
or give it commands.
I can ask something like, "Is there
anything that needs my attention right
now?" And since it knows me and my
business and has access to all my tools,
it will be able to see if I need to answer
emails, if I have meetings coming up.
Is there a new lead in my pipeline?
Do I need to follow up with someone?
A simple, vague prompt like that
is all the AI needs because it
has all the context it needs.
You don't have to prompt
engineer anything here.
You can just talk to it like
you would talk to a colleague
So to illustrate this, I'm just gonna
have it look through some of my trusted
sources, which I have predefined, and
see if it can find any content ideas that
would be relevant for me and my brand
So as you can see, it's now running
the task for me, and while we wait for
that, I can just show you the dashboard
that also comes with this system.
This is more of like a visual
layer to the AI operating system,
and this gives you just a quick
overview of what is happening.
So I have a dashboard here I can view
daily, which just gives me an overview
of what needs to happen, like the
follow-ups I need to do or the emails
that need my attention right away.
Do I have anything booked in the calendar?
I'm not gon- I'm not gonna click
it now because there's, you know,
obviously private information there.
But I also have things like
how is my system performing?
Uh, check, you know, the latest audit.
How well did the latest audit do?
This is just a nice visual layer to have.
I wouldn't say it's essential, um,
'cause most of the time I spend here
in the chat window And here we have a
visual representation of the memory.
You can see here all the information that
gets stored gets connected like this.
So it doesn't have, you know, a piece
of information just stored in isolation.
It, it connects all the information
it gets in a meaningful way, and
this is just a cool way to illustrate
how the AI system lear-- or the AI
operating system learns over time.
It makes these different connections
as, you teach it things, as it
gets smarter, as it learns your
business and how you do things
So here it's done.
It's gone through my sources and looked
for any changes in the last 48 hours, if
they posted anything new, and it has then
suggested ideas for content I could do.
And this is all filtered through,
my business, what is relevant for
me, what is relevant for my clients.
Is there anything I need to take
note of that might improve my
services or anything like that?
And you can see, I can just go through
this, and if there's anything that
catches my eye, I can just simply
tell AI to execute on the idea.
If it's a piece of content, I can tell
it, "Hey, can you draft out a piece of
content based on this?" Uh, and it will
have access to everything it needs.
It knows my voice, it knows my history.
It has access to case studies.
So you don't get that
typical generic stuff.
Or if it is like a technical thing
I can tell, "Hey, can we update our
system and try this out, run a trial
period with this new, uh, framework
we found?" Or something like that.
So it's just insanely useful for
me, uh, to be able to do this.
But this is just, one of hundreds
of examples of what you can
do with an AI operating system
So as you saw in my demo, I was working
within a chat window that looked very
similar to what you might be used
to, something like ChatGPT or Claude.
But the difference here is
that this is not a regular
chatbot, it's an agent harness.
You might have heard of these.
These are called Claude Code, uh, Claude
Cowork, or, uh, OpenAI's, uh, Codex.
These are all agent harnesses.
And the only thing you need to know
about these is that this is where we
will contain the AI operating system.
This is where we will have all
the necessary files that the AI
need to access, all the scripts
the AI need to execute tasks.
Which agent harness you decide to
use depends entirely on taste and
preferences and how technical you are.
They all essentially do the same thing.
They're just slight variations
to how they function
and I really wanna drive home
the point that the AI operating
system only gets better over time.
Unlike traditional tech stocks
that gets more bloated and complex
over time, the AI operating system
operates in the complete opposite way.
It finds inefficiencies, it
finds the way you prefer to
work, and optimizes for that.
It removes inefficiencies and bottlenecks,
and the more you use it, the better it
becomes at doing this That's why after
a while, your operating system is going
to look completely different from your
competitor's operating system as it will
be tailored to your specific business.
Yes, the foundation of how to build an
AI operating system technically will
always remain the same, but it's when
you're using it, you're really starting
to make it your own, and that's where
the real value in the system comes in
So the next obvious question then
becomes how do we build this practically?
And the way I recommend approaching this
is to just build this for one person
to begin with, and that is usually the
founder And once we have that foundation,
we can simply replicate what we build
and give each team member their own
version of that AI operating system
of course, all these systems across
your team is going to have shared
context across your entire business.
But each member has the ability now to
customize their operating system to how
they like to work because no two people
like to work in the exact same way.
This way you essentially give your team
superpowers and instead of replacing
your team with AI, you're actually
making your team more effective
So how do we get started building your own
version one of the AI operating system?
Well, it always starts in the same
way, and that is with an AI audit.
And I know no one wants to do an
audit, but it's absolutely necessary to
understand how your business work, what
processes, um, you have, what software
you use, how the data flows, and then map
out where are the inefficiencies, where
are the bottlenecks, and then we can rank
them based on how much they impact revenue
and how much of a time sink they are.
That way, when we build out the AI
operating system, we know where to start
for you to see results as quickly as
possible If you wanna build out your own
AI operating system, I'd love to help.
You can reach me via email or shoot me
a DM over at LinkedIn, or you can just
go to my official website and click on
the Book a Free Call button to book in
a call to see if we're a good fit Either
way, I hope this has inspired you and
given you some ideas for how you can
implement AI into your own business, and
finally see some real results with AI